我们来谈谈我们如何找到线要素。在这个例子中我们拍了一张照片
Let's talk about how we find line features. In this example here we've taken a picture
一个教堂，并在该图像上叠加了许多线条。这些线条依旧存在
of a church and have overlaid a number of lines onto that image. These lines lay along
场景中明显的界限。
the obvious boundaries in the scene.
天空与屋顶，屋顶和墙壁，边缘和窗户之间的边界等
The boundary between the sky and the roof, roof and the wall, edges and windows and so
上。我们该怎么做呢？第一步是我们采用原始输入图像，
on. How do we go about doing this? The first step is we take our original input image,
我们将其转换为灰度图像，然后我们执行年龄提取操作。
we convert it to a gray scale image and then we perform an age extraction operation.
我们在之前的讲座中讨论过边缘算子。它主要涉及卷积
We talked about edge operators in a previous lecture. It involved essentially a convolutional
确定图像渐变的过程，然后我们应用一些阈值。
process to determine image gradients and then we apply some threshold to that.
这个图像看起来非常令人印象深刻，我们可以清楚地看到所有明显的线条
This image looks very impressive in a way we can clearly see that all the obvious lines
在这里突出显示图像。但请记住，这只是一张图片。它包含一个
in the image are highlighted here. But remember that this is just an image. It contains a
整个像素。有些像素是黑色，有些像素是白色。实际上有
whole lot of pixels. Some pixels are black and some pixels are white. There is actually
这里没有线的概念。
no concept of line here.
我们的眼睛看到了场景中的线条，我们的眼睛和大脑非常非常
Our eyes are seeing lines within the scene and our eyes and our brain are very, very
擅长这样做，但实际上这里没有线条的概念。这只是一堆
good at doing this but there is actually no notion of lines here. It is simply a bunch
白色像素和黑色像素，白色像素突出显示有意义的地方
of white pixels and black pixels and the white pixels highlight where there is significant
场景中的渐变。
gradient within the scene.
那么我们如何在这里找到长线段呢？我们如何将这些白色像素分组为线条
So how do we find the long line segments here? How do we group these white pixels into lines
我们可以通过一个简单的方程来描述。Y=mx+b中。我们这样做的方式是使用图像
which we can describe by a simple equation. y=mx+b. The way we do this is with an image
处理技术称为霍夫变换，它非常非常巧妙，我想尝试
processing technique called the Hough transform and it's very, very ingenious and I want to try
并尽可能简单地解释它。
and explain it as simply as I can.
让我们假设我们有一个优势点。所以这可能是一个沿着像素的像素
Let's imagine that we have one edge point. So this might be a pixel that's along the
我们刚刚看到的教堂的屋顶，一个像素放在边缘。
roof of the church that we were just looking at, a single pixel which lays on an edge.
现在有无限数量的线可以穿过空间中的任何点。这条线
Now there are infinite number of lines which can go through any point in space. This line
例如，经过这一点，这条线没有通过，这条线确实去了
for instance goes through the point, this line does not go through, this line does go
通过，这一个没有，这一个没有，这一个确实，这一个确实和这一个
through, this one doesn't, this one does, this one does, this one does and this one
确实。
does.
现在我们可以考虑这些线路投票。这条线没有通过
Now we could consider that the lines vote for the point. This line doesn't go through
这一点，所以不允许投票。获得零票。然后这行
the point so it's not allowed to vote for the point. It gets zero votes. Then this line
获得零票;它没有经过这一点。但这条线得到投票等等
gets zero votes as well; it doesn't go through the point. But this line gets a vote and so
做这个，这一个，这个和这一个。
does this one, this one, this one and this one.
这些线路投了这一点，红线没有投票。
These lines voted for the point and the red lines have not voted for the point.
现在，让我们考虑一下我们还有另一个沿着边缘铺设的点，也许是这两个黑色
Now, lets consider we have another point which lays along the edge perhaps these two black
现在，我们正在看着教堂的屋顶。再一次在那里
points now lay along the roof of the church that we were just looking at. Once again there
是无限数量的线，可以通过这一点。可能是这条线，
are an infinite number of lines which could go through that point. Could be this line,
或者这一行，或者这一行再一次，我们将允许这些行投票
or this line, or this line and once again, we are going to allow the lines to vote for
一个点。
a point.
所以这条线得到一票，因为它经过一个点，这条线获得投票
So this line gets one vote because it goes through a point, this line gets a vote as
做这一个和这个，但这一行也经历了第一点。
does this one and this one but this line also goes through that first point.
该特定线现在有两票。但是我们看到这里有很多行
That particular line now has two votes. But we see that there are a lot of lines in this
现场，我已经画了一小部分。有无穷无尽的行数
scene and I have already drawn up a small number. There are a infinite number of lines
通过点，无限数量的线不通过点。
that go through the points, infinite number of lines that don't go through the points.
我们可以看到，经过一个点的一些线得到一票但只有一个特别
We can see that some of the lines that go through a point get one vote but one particular
线，经过两分的线获得两票。所以我们使用了简单的投票
line, the line that goes through two points gets two votes. So we've used a simple voting
系统试图确定经过两点的最佳线，我们可以扩展
system to try and determine the best line that goes through two points and we can extend
这对于大量的点来说就是我们在处理图像时会做的事情
this to a large number of points and that's what we would do when we process an image
像教堂一样。通常，当我们表示线时，我们使用这样的等式。这个
like the church. Normally when we represent lines, we use an equation like this. This
是一条线的非常标准的笛卡尔表示。U是我们的水平坐标，
is the very standard Cartesian representation of a line. U is our horizontal coordinate,
V是我们的垂直坐标，M是梯度，C是截距。这个问题
V is our vertical coordinate, M is the gradient and C is the intercept. A problem with this
线的特定表示是垂直线。在行的情况下
particular representation of a line is for vertical lines. In the case where the line
是垂直的，它必须等于无穷大，这有点问题。
is vertical, it must be equal to infinity and that's slightly problematic.
还有另一种方法我们可以描述一条线的方程式，我们就是这样做的
There is another way we can describe the equation of a line and we do it in this fashion, it's
通常称为线的极坐标表示我们有U和V坐标但是
often called the polar representation of a line that we have a U and V coordinates but
该线由两个参数rho和theta描述。Theta是角度
the line is described by two parameters now rho and theta. Theta is the angle that the
线与水平轴和rho之间的垂直距离
line makes with the horizontal axis and rho is the perpendicular distance between the
起源和线上的一点。两个参数rho和theta可以描述更多的线
origin and a point on the line. Two parameters rho and theta can describe a line in a more
比传统的渐变和截距配方更通用的方式。
versatile way than the traditional gradient and intercept formulation.
一个问题是当我们谈论所有那些无限数量的线路时
One problem is when we are talking about all those infinite number of lines that could
经历一个观点是无数次投票难以投票。什么
go through a point is its going to be difficult for an infinite number of lines to vote. What
我们需要做的是量化rho和theta的值。而不是考虑无限
we need to do is to quantize the values of rho and theta. Instead of considering an infinite
我们认为有限行数的行数。
number of lines we consider a finite number of lines.
它是这样工作的，它是一个投票方案，现在我们有一个坐标系，横轴
It works like this, it's a voting scheme now we have a coordinate system, horizontal axis
是theta的线参数，纵轴是rho的线参数。和我们
is the line parameter of theta, the vertical axis is the line parameter of rho. And we
在这上面放了一个网格。每个单元格代表图像中的可能线条。一个特别的
placed a grid on this. Every single cell represents a possible line in an image. A particular
行的值和theta的特定值，表示图像中的一条线。这个
value of row and a particular value of theta and that represents a line in the image. This
在现实世界的例子中，这个网格可能有数百个元素
is a very course example in a real world example this grid might have hundreds of elements
在两个方向。要记住的重要一点是
in both directions. The important thing to keep in mind is that
每个单元格代表图像中的特定线条。
each cell represents a particular line within the image.
对于输入图像中沿边缘放置的任何点，这是坐标U处的像素
For any point in the input image, that lays along an edge, that's a pixel at coordinate U
和V通过该点的线的参数必须满足该特定方程。
and V the parameters of the lines that go through that point must satisfy this particular equation.
现在这是一个将rho与theta联系起来的方程式。对于theta的每个可能的值，
This is now an equation that relates rho to theta. For every possible value of theta,
鉴于我知道U和V，我可以计算出rho的值。所有这些线都得到了
given that I know U and V, I can computer a value of rho. And so all these lines get
投票。他们可以为该特定行投一票。对于这一点，它提出
to have a vote. They get to vote one for that particular line. For this one point, it puts
这些投票进入我们称之为投票数组的投票数组，有时称为霍夫累加器。
these votes into what we call the voting array sometimes called the Hough accumulator.
所以有一点我们已经为大量的线路投了票。现在让我们考虑一下
So for one point we have made votes for a large number of lines. Now let's consider
当我们引入第二点时会发生什么。第二点是对所有人投票
what happens when we introduce a second point. The second point is voting for all of the
通过它的可能线条，它在投票中引入了另一条曲线
possible lines that pass through it and it's introduced another curve into the voting
阵列。我们可以看到，有一些可能的线路得到一票和我们
array. We can see that there are a number of possible lines that got one vote and we
可以看到这里有一条线有两票。这是潜在的
can see that there is one line here which has got two votes. This is the underlying
霍夫变换的原理。
principle for the Hough transform.